<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- DO NOT CHANGE THIS FILE!! IT WAS GENERATED AUTOMATICALLY! (you must edit files in help_template directory) -->
<Document style="helpdocument">
	<p style="htitle">Controls</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'F1' to open the help window.</p>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Map Navigation</p>
	<p style="hp">Move around the map with the arrow keys, the keypad ('1', '2', '3', '4', '6', '7', '8', '9'), or WASD. Hold SHIFT to move faster.</p>
	<p style="hp">Pan by dragging with the middle mouse button.</p>
	<p style="hp">Move the mouse to the edge of the screen to move in that direction.</p>
	<p style="hp">Move to the center of the map by pressing '5' on the keypad.</p>
	<p style="hp">Click on the minimap to move to the selected area of the map.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'P' to center the screen on a construction. (Can be useful for finding a small village in a large map.) Press 'P' again to cycle through which construction to center the screen on.</p>
	<p style="hp">Zoom in and out by scrolling or pressing '+' or '-' on the keypad. Press ENTER on the keypad to reset zoom to 100%.</p>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Building</p>
	<p style="hp">Use the mouse (left button) to select a module from the menu on the left side. Once a module is selected, left-click on the map to build it.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'B' to switch to the bulldoze tool. With the bulldoze tool activated, left-click on a construction to bulldoze it. Press 'B' again to switch back.</p>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Query Tool</p>
	<p style="hp">Press ESC to activate the query tool. Use the query tool by left-clicking on a construction to show information about it. Clicking the same construction again will toggle the kind of information shown. You can use the query tool without activating it by using the right mouse button instead of the left.</p>
	<p style="hp">Note: On markets and ports, clicking a second time will bring up the trade dialog.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'G' to toggle showing information about the tile underneath a construction, e.g. pollution information.</p>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Mini-Map and Overlay</p>
	<p style="hp">Press '1' through '9' or backtick('`') to select the mini-map mode. Pressing '7' will toggle between the traffic and commodity modes. You can also change the mode by clicking on the buttons below the mini-map.</p>
	<p style="hp">While in the traffic or commodity mini-map mode, cycle through commodities by hovering over the mini-map and scrolling. You can also cycle commodities by clicking the up/down arrow buttons by the upper-right corner on the mini-map or by pressing 'M'/'N'.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'H' to show/hide tall buildings.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'V' to cycle overlay modes (off -&gt; transparent -&gt; opaque -&gt; off).</p>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Simulation</p>
	<p style="hp">Press the buttons in the lower-left corner of the screen to change the simulation speed or exit to the main menu. From the main menu, you can save your progress.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'F12' to quick-save.</p>
	<p style="hp">Press 'F9' to quick-load.</p>

  <p style="hsubtitle">See also:</p>
	<li><a href="button-index">Select button index</a></li>
	<li><a href="bulldoze">Bulldoze</a></li>
	<li><a href="query">Query</a></li>
	<li><a href="mini-screen">Minimap</a></li>
</Document>
