<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- DO NOT CHANGE THIS FILE!! IT WAS GENERATED AUTOMATICALLY! (you must edit files in help_template directory) -->
<Document style="helpdocument">
	<p style="htitle">Ports</p>
	<p style="hp">Ports let you import and export goods, steel, ore, coal and food. Importing costs you money and exporting makes you money.</p>
	<p style="hp">You choose what to import by double clicking on the port. This brings up a menu with boxes to select what to import and what to export. If "buy" and "sell" are both checked or both unchecked for a commodity, then that commodity will not be imported or exported.</p>
	<p style="hp">They must be connected to rivers all along the right hand side.</p>
	<p style="hp">Nothing will be imported or exported until you have checked the appropriate box.</p>
	<p style="hp">The export area will take as much as it is given. If you need to export, but want to restrict the amount, you may want to use a type of transport with less capacity, use a long piece or pass the product through a market. You will need to experiment to get the right transport configuration.</p>
	<p style="hp">An active Port provides some technology. Note: Exporters discount large exports.</p>

  <p style="hp">This is a port</p>
   <img src="images/tiles/ex_port.png" halign="center"/>

  <p style="hp">and this its icon</p>
   <img src="images/gui/buttonpanel/transport/port.png" halign="center"/>

	<p style="hsubtitle">Formulas</p>
	<p style="hp">export: 50% of inventory =&gt; money</p>
	<p style="hp">import: money =&gt; 50% of remaining capacity</p>
	<p style="hp">For import or export to occur, 100 labor must be consumed.</p>
	<p style="hp">If there is both import and export, then .0002 tech is produced, which can sustain up to ~10 tech <100 or ~5 tech >100.</p>
	<p style="hp">If there is less than 6.67% inventory of a commodity, then export does not occur. If there is more than 93.33% inventory of a commodity, then import does not occur.</p>

  <p style="hsubtitle">See also:</p>
	<li><a href="export">Import and export areas</a></li>
	<li><a href="river">Rivers/Water</a></li>
	<li><a href="transport">Transport</a></li>
	<li><a href="market">Market</a></li>
	<li><a href="food">Food</a></li>
	<li><a href="coal">Coal</a></li>
	<li><a href="ore">Ore</a></li>
	<li><a href="goods">Goods</a></li>
	<li><a href="steel">Steel</a></li>
</Document>